Check this out.
大家看哈
This is a
这是一个那个
small, fully automated
全自动的
clothing production workshop.
小型的服装生产车间
As we're considering launching
咱们既然要做一个
a pilot project,
试点呢
I believe it's essential for our company
我觉着企业呢
to have a full-fledged factory,
一定要有自己的厂房
not just a pilot.
不是仅仅只有一个试点
Okay,
好
let's take a look.
大家看一下
Excuse me.
对不起 我电话
Okay, I'm going to continue.
我接着说啊
This equipment can
这套设备呢
make a three-dimensional cut cashmere coat
一次性就可以做一个
all in one go.
立体剪裁的羊绒大衣
If we get an order
如果订单呢
for over 100 pieces,
超过一百件呢
it's definitely enough.
它完全够用了
Plus, it will significantly shorten
而且这能大大地缩短
our fashion brand's
我们的
production cycle,
时尚品牌的运转周期
and we'll be more flexible and responsive
然后在设计方面呢
to the market in terms of design.
更加灵活地面对市场
Let me show you again.
我再给大家演示一遍啊
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
are you messing around
你是不跟
with the nanny?
保姆搞一块儿去了
Are you socializing or babysitting?
聊天呢 还是带孩子呢
Mrs Jia.
太太
At the postpartum care center,
在月子中心的时候
I sensed something fishy
我就发现你
between you and Haowen.
和老贾有问题
You hand-held Haowen
手把手地
how to bathe
教他给孩子洗澡
to my baby.
教他给孩子抹油
When Xiongxiong was born,
之前生熊熊的时候
Haowen knew exactly what to do.
老贾什么都会
But in front of you,
怎么一碰到你
he seems clueless, and you have to
就什么都不会了
guide him through everything.
还要手把手地教
You were supposed to care for me
你说你个月嫂
during my maternity period, but did you?
你照顾我了吗
All you do is
你每天就知道
please my husband
哄我老公
and my mother-in-law.
哄我婆婆高兴
Are you here to work,
你是来干活的吗
or are you here to be the mistress?
你是来当女主人的吧
Xin, please don't be upset.
心心 你别生气
I sent this scarf
这个围巾
to Shanshan as a gift.
是我送给珊珊的
You are solely focused on
你每天就知道
your granddaughter.
我孙女好不好
"Did my granddaughter eat well today?"
我孙女今天吃得怎么样
"How did my granddaughter sleep today?"
我孙女今天睡得怎么样
"Did my granddaughter drink well today?"
我孙女今天喝得好不好
All you do is to
你每天就知道
coddle your granddaughter.
哄着你孙女
What about me?
我呢 我呢
Can you see me?
你眼里有我吗
So here comes this woman
现在好了
who's good at cooking,
来了一个饭做得好
babysitting,
孩子带得好
and always by your side,
还能跟您站在一边
picking on me.
欺负我的
Now, she's even wearing
这现在同款丝巾
the same scarf as I do.
都戴上了
What's next?
这接下来怎么着
Will she start sleeping in my bedroom
这要睡我卧室
and taking care of my daughter?
照顾我女儿啊
Please don't get upset, Mrs Jia.
太太
It's only been a little over a month
这刚做完手术一个多月
since your C-section surgery.
生气会伤身体
You still get it, right?
你还知道伤身体啊
You still know that
你还知道我是太太啊
Then why are you
那你天天围着她转
always around her?
干什么
Don't think I don't know
你别以为我不知道
what you're up to.
你安的什么心
If you want to be the mistress,
你想当女主人你直说呀
Mrs Jia,
太太
I am a
我是一个接受过
professionally trained
专业培训的
maternity matron.
母婴护理师
I rely on my skills,
是靠本事工作的
not tricks, to do my job well.
不是靠那些歪门邪道
If that's your opinion of me,
既然您这么认为我
then I see no reason
那我也没有必要
to stay here any longer.
在这里继续待下去了
No reason to stay here any longer?
你没有必要继续待
I think you're doing quite well here.
我看你待着挺好的
You seemed very relaxed
这说说笑笑的
while chatting and laughing just now.
其乐融融的嘛
Ma'am,
阿姨
thank you.
谢谢您
Shanshan,
珊珊 别别
don't go.
别
Why are you leaving?
你别走啊
You seemed so sure of yourself just now.
你不是有道理吗
Or I can leave to let you stay.
不行我走也行啊
Mom,
妈
Ying,
英子姐
the baby's here.
这孩子在这儿呢
Why don't you stop chatting
你们别聊天了
and take care of the baby?
照顾照顾孩子 不好吗
Seriously, take a good look at yourself.
看你这个熊样
It's obvious that you're not
就知道你没有把心思
committed to the company.
放在公司上啊
The shareholders' meeting today
今天的股东会议啊
was supposed to
本来是我替你
demonstrate how dedicated you are.
开给股东们看的
Rumors are going around.
外边有些风言风语
I wanted to boost
我是要增强
their confidence in your investments.
他们对你的投资信心
What made them
兄弟们为什么
invest in you?
给你投资啊
What was the reason?
为啥呀
It wasn't just your
不是看你的品牌
brand name.
做得有多大
It was your integrity.
是看你的为人
They wanted to know
看你贾浩文这个人品
if they could trust you.
到底靠不靠谱
But look at what you've done.
你倒好
You've disgraced yourself.
你把脸都丢尽啦
You've become the butt of jokes.
让所有的人看你的笑话
I've also become a joke.
我也成了笑话
I can't cover you any longer.
以后我也罩不住你了
Take care of yourself.
好自为之吧
How can my mom ask me
你说我妈凭什么
to forgive Zhu Kexin?
让我原谅朱可欣啊
Yes, Zhu Kexin cheated on the test
对啊 朱可欣那么对你
and framed you.
她还自己作弊
Why should you forgive her?
你为什么要原谅她
Yeah.
就是
I used the trick you taught me.
我用了你教我的那招
Which one?
哪一招啊
I taught you a lot of tricks.
我教你招可多了
My mom said that
我妈说
Zhu Kexin is
朱可欣
her mom's only hope.
是她妈唯一的希望
So, I said,
那我就说
"Yes, she's her only hope,
对 她是唯一的希望
but I'm different.
我不一样啊
You've got a second child now.
你现在都有老二了
You've got other hopes."
还有别的希望呢
I don't expect you to
我教你这招
use that trick in that manner.
不是让你用在这儿的呀
So,
那你
what's your next move?
现在打算怎么办呀
What options do I have?
我能怎么办呀
Actually,
其实
I not unreasonable.
我也不是不讲道理
I don't want Zhu Kexin to get in
我总不能
serious trouble and be banned from taking
真让朱可欣背处分
the High School Entrance Examination.
不能参加中考吧
I just want to stand up to my mom;
我就想跟我妈争口气
she should be on my side
谁让她胳膊肘往外拐啊
instead of speaking for Zhu Kexin.
她应该站在我这边的
He Lu,
何璐
are you talking about that incident?
是说那个事呢吗
Yes, what's wrong?
对啊 怎么了
You weren't present then,
你当时不在场
but I was there the whole time.
我可是全程都在的
Yunjie,
云阶
your parents, especially your mom,
你爸 你妈
really stood by you.
真刚
If she hadn't insisted, how could the
要不是她一直挺你
school have redone the investigation
怎么可能调查出来
and proven that Zhu Kexin cheated?
是朱可欣做的弊
What?
什么事啊
Tell me more.
赶快跟我说说
At first,
一开始啊
Ms Xue
薛老师
went to Yunjie's parents
找云阶爸爸妈妈
and claimed they found a cheat sheet
就说是从云阶抽屉里
in Yunjie's drawer.
发现了小抄
The CCTV footage confirmed that
而且监控也显示
the inspector found it
就是巡考老师
from Yunjie's drawer,
从云阶抽屉里发现的
so, it was basically a closed case.
板上钉钉的事
I didn't do that.
可那不是
I know.
是
Your mom
是你妈妈
chose to believe in you and insisted that
选择信任你
the cheat sheet didn't belong to you.
坚定认为小抄不是你的
She pushed for a re-investigation
要求重新调查
and demanded that Ms Xue
还要求薛老师
confront Zhu Kexin's mom
让朱可欣妈妈来对质
before the truth finally came out,
才真相大白的
didn't she?
对不对
The most important thing
这里面最重要的
here is that
环节就是
your parents
你爸你妈
believe in you unconditionally
无条件相信你
and support you.
挺你
If it were my dad,
要是换成我爸
he would've just given me a good beating
肯定不由分说
without hearing me out,
给我一顿胖揍
and maybe even
说不定
kicked me into the river.
还一脚给我踹江里呢
Yeah,
对
my parents
要是我爸妈
would suspect me first.
肯定首先怀疑我
Even if they reluctantly trusted that
就算是最后
I didn't do it,
勉强相信不是我干的
they'd be like,
但他们肯定也会说
"Why are they only
为什么人家就怀疑你
suspecting you?
不怀疑别人啊
Maybe you should
你得从你自己身上
take a good look at yourself."
找问题
That's true.
对
As the saying goes,
俗话说得好
flies don't bite a seamless egg.
苍蝇不叮无缝的蛋
Yeah, they love this saying.
对 就是这一句
My mom also used to say this
我妈也说过这句话
when she talked about Liu Siming.
就用在刘思明身上
What did she say about me?
说我什么
Nothing.
没事 没事
Let's go.
走吧
Okay.
走
I'm telling you that flies are not good.
我跟你说苍蝇真的不好
Flies are cool.
苍蝇多好啊
What's wrong with flies?
苍蝇怎么了
They are good at flying.
苍蝇善于飞行
They can fly six to
每小时能飞
eight kilometers an hour.
六到八公里呢
I'd love to be a fly
我都想当只苍蝇
and zoom around fast.
飞得还快
Excuse me,
你好
ma'am.
这位美女
I'm sorry to bother you.
你好 你好 你好
Do you know where Liu Siming's class is?
这个刘思明在哪儿上课
I'm his dad.
我是他爸
Please wait for a moment.
您稍等一下
Mr Liu,
老刘
No, forget it.
不用了 不用了
Lin,
李老弟啊
it's been a long time.
好久没见啊
Yeah.
是
It's been a long time since we met.
咱俩好久不见啊
That's true.
是是是 是
I haven't met you since your family moved.
搬走之后没见过了
Same here.
是 是
But I saw your wife once.
你媳妇我倒是见过
It's on the event
就是
when my son
我儿子给你女儿
gave flowers to your daughter.
献花那回
Well,
老刘
we still have some time
这个 这正好啊
before the kids' class ends.
他们上课还得有一会儿
It's been ages since we've met each other.
我们也好久没见了
Let's find a place
找个地儿
to have some tea and catch up.
我请你喝茶 聊聊
Great!
好啊
Xin,
心心
why'd you come back all of a sudden?
你怎么突然回来了
What's with the sudden return?
什么叫突然回来呀
Mom, do you not want me to come back home?
我回自己家 不欢迎啊
No, you're entirely welcome!
好 欢迎 欢迎
Why all the packages?
这大包小包的
Did you and Haowen have another fight?
是不又和浩文吵架了
Why do you always assume that?
什么意思呀
Every time I return,
是不是我一回来
you think it's due to a fight with him.
就是跟他吵架了
That's pretty much the case every time.
差不多呀
Didn't I tell you that
我不是跟你说了吗
I didn't fight with him?
没有
I told you about that.
我不是说了吗
With the maternity matron quitting
月嫂走了
and no one taking care of the baby,
孩子没人带了
where else can I go
那我不回娘家
other than here?
我上哪儿去啊
Alright, having you back is good.
对对对 回来对了
You'll be more comfortable at home.
家里多舒服呀 是吧
Lanxiang and I will take care of the baby
孩子我和兰香帮你带
so, you can stay here comfortably.
你就舒舒服服地待着
I'm hungry.
我饿了
What do you want to eat?
吃啥
Small wontons.
小馄饨
Sure, I'll ask Lanxiang to make them.
我叫兰香煮去
Bro,
老刘啊
you're still your usual self,
你还是当年的你啊
guzzling beers like they're water.
拿啤酒当水喝啊
Yeah, absolutely.
必须的
I get concerned sometimes that Siming,
我有时候还有点担心呢
the same way you are.
我就怕思明啊 随了你
Definitely.
那他必须得随啊
drinking habits.
喝酒
The influence of genetics and
那 这是什么叫基因
the impact of family traits is strong.
什么叫遗传
Hey, look at this.
看看 看看
Do you see it?
看见没
Where do you think this came from?
这哪儿来的
I see it, I see it.
看见了 看见了
Siming's impressive speed
他现在能跑那么快
on the racetrack
那不就是遗
is inherited from me.
遗传了我的基因吗
Although I was
当然 虽然我当年
slower than he is now,
成绩没他现在这么好
my athletic genes played a role in him.
但是没有我
Like father, like son.
有其父必有其子啊
It's a widely accepted theory.
这是在论的呀 对不对
Although Siming
我们家儿子
got the athletic genes from me,
虽然说随了我的基因
ever since childhood, he's been saying,
但是 从小就跟我说
"See Uncle Li
你看看人李叔叔
and his wife, both graduates of
人家俩人
top universities. You should
都是名牌大学毕业的
aim for higher education like them."
你学学人家 有点文化
I don't have the academic genes. If I did,
我 我要学会了
I might have gone to a top university.
我 我也名牌大学了
Listen,
但是我要跟你说
I think
我觉得思明
Siming is a really nice
还是个好孩子
and motivated child.
也挺要进步的
Totally.
那当然
He's got his whole future in front of him.
还有发展的空间
Yeah, I agree.
有
I've seen
我也是从小
Siming grow up.
看到思明长大的
Yeah.
是
You know it, do you?
是不是
Siming gets along well
跟我们家闺女
with my daughter, Yunjie.
关系也挺好
They're very close.
特别好
Siming is a kid who values friendship
重情义
and is very loyal.
讲义气
They're both good kids.
都很好
But, you know, they're both
但是 现在孩子他们呀
still pretty young.
还太小
Not at all. Siming is like 5'11" already.
小什么啊 都一米八了
And Yunjie has grown so much.
你女儿也亭亭玉立了
Is she 14 now?
也十 十 十四
She and Siming are both 15 years old.
跟你思明一样 十五嘛
Yeah.
对对 对啊
In the past, people this age could have
那早年间人家都可以
already been married and had kids.
结婚生孩子了
It's in modern times.
现在是现在的事
The kids are keeping up with the times.
人家那与时俱进呢
Listen...
这 这个
Why are you holding them up for?
你还等什么呀
If they're dating,
真有
it's their business.
人家孩子愿意
Why should we interfere with
怎么着怎么着
what the kids want?
这就顺其自然
Let it be.
跟咱们有什么关系啊
For some critical matters,
有些事
we can't just let it be.
它可不能顺其自然哪
They're in the last year of middle school,
现在他们是初三
preparing for
马上就要中考了
the High School Entrance Examination,
对他们来说
which is a big deal
这是他们人生中
for them.
非常重要的一步
They've got a long way to go,
人生路漫漫哪
but every step
但是每一步
has to be solid.
必须要走夯实了
I hope
那我希望他们
they both
他们两个孩子
put all their energy and time
都把所有的精力和时间
into their studies
花在学习上
to make progress together.
共同进步
Don't you think it's a good idea?
这不好吗
No worries.
没事
Am I right?
是不是
Siming is a good kid,
我们家孩子
so, I'm not worried about him.
再差也差不到哪儿去了
Yunjie, your daughter,
咱家闺女那好得是
is also very good, so we shouldn't
那特别好
worry too much about her either.
不怕 不怕
I mean,
你看
your family has moved
你们都搬家了
so far away.
搬得那么老远
Why not find a school nearby
你说思明为什么就不在
for Siming?
附近找个学上
I want him to go to
我也想让他去
a top middle school, too.
上个重点中学
Siming's talent in racing
我儿子那速度
will get him into
他想上哪个重点
any top high school.
不 不容易啊
However, he doesn't want to go.
这 人家不
He only wants to go to the same school
你女儿去哪儿他去哪儿
as your daughter. What can I do?
这我管得了吗
That's...
这这 这不
Let's not meddle in their business.
咱 咱都别管
For this matter,
我觉得这个事
as parents,
孩子的家长
I think we must
我们 作为我们来说
step in here.
我们一定要管
They are in a stage of immaturity
孩子现在还在一个
where they are not ready to
逐渐成熟的阶段
make certain decisions, are they?
是不是
For some matters,
有些事
we should be the ones
我们要说了算
making decisions for them.
我们要给他们做主
There are some boundaries
不行
they cannot cross.
那就是不行
I'm not entirely convinced.
有什么不行的
No,
不
you don't understand.
你不懂
I mean,
你看
you're raising a boy.
你养的是儿子
So, you don't get my point.
你就不明白这个道理
Okay.
对
I'm raising a girl.
我是闺女
Yeah, a daughter.
小棉袄
Yunjie holds great significance for me.
对 不仅是小棉袄
Siming is a boy. He is easy to raise
你个儿子 你随便养
and can thrive with less care.
散养都可以
But Yunjie is a girl,
但是闺女不一样
and I cherish her deeply.
她是我心头肉
She's like the rose
她是爸爸
I planted in my past life.
前世种下的玫瑰啊
She requires dedicated care
她需要呵护
and a fertile environment to thrive.
需要泥土
I can't let a delicate flower
她不能够一朵鲜花
be stuck in
她就这莫名其妙
in...
她就插在
Wait, are you implying that
你说说说 什么意思
Yunjie is a flower
就是你们家那朵花
while Siming
不能插在我们家的
is cow dung?
牛粪上呗
I'm not saying that.
我 我可没这么说
How can I get married to my wife
那我媳妇不就
if a flower can't bloom on cow dung?
插我这泡粪上了吗
No,
不不
that's a different case.
这个粪和那个粪不一样
You get me wrong.
不不不
I got it.
那我肯定
Your main point is not about cow dung.
不是粪不粪的
So, your concern is that
说一千道一万
they might develop a relationship, right?
你不就是怕孩子早恋吗
Yes.
对啊
If they both have a crush on each other,
那人俩互相喜欢
I won't get involved.
我管不了
But if Siming dares to take the crush to
但是
the next level, I will beat him.
他敢早恋 我先练他
Is that okay?
行不行
That's a deal.
那可说好了
Deal.
一言为定
You must keep an eye on Siming.
可得看住了
Cheer.
你喝水
Actually, I don't mind
其实 我也不介意
being your in-law.
跟你当个亲家
But I do mind.
我介意啊
Mrs Xu,
大姨
Mr Xu,
老爷子
look at this.
看
I bought two fresh fish at the pier.
我到码头上买的鲜鱼
One for Meng'an to take home
一条给梦安带回去
and another for us to...
一条咱一会儿
oops, the bag is leaking water.
淌水呢
Little Watermelon's here.
小西瓜来啦
Oh my God,
天哪
you're here.
你来啦
Hold on, hold on.
等会儿 等会儿 等 等
When did you...
你什么时候
Wait a moment.
等会儿
Don't touch her now.
手 手 手
I forgot it.
对对对
First, disinfect my hands.
消毒 消毒
Let me do it.
消毒
Yeah.
是是是
Babies
小孩啊
have weak immune systems, do they?
抵抗力弱是吧
Let's make sure to
消毒
disinfect my hands.
消消毒 好嘞
I've finished cooking the wontons.
馄饨 我做好了啊
Great.
做好了
Disinfect.
消消毒
Jing.
姐
Where are you off to?
你这干吗去啊
I'm taking Uncle to his rehab training.
我领叔出去康复去
Let's get going.
咱走了啊
Let's go, Uncle.
走了啊 叔
Come on.
咱走啦
You've got this!
对 对
Come on, Little Watermelon.
小西瓜
Give it your all to kick your legs.
使劲往下蹬 使劲往下蹬
That's it.
对
Give it your best shot.
使劲
Mr Xu,
老爷子
you need to do your rehab training.
你得好好去康复
Come on.
快走吧
Let's go.
走啊
I'm not up for the rehab training today.
今天不康复了
That's not cool.
这可不行啊
Mr Xu,
老爷子
You must take your
这个康复的事啊
rehab training seriously
一定要认真
and care for your body.
咱得加把油
I mean,
你看
you already have Little Watermelon.
我们都有了小西瓜啦
When Meng'an has
这个梦安再生一个
Little Grape,
小葡萄
Little Grape and Little Watermelon
小西瓜 小葡萄
will run around the yard.
满院子跑
Yeah.
对
Take it easy.
慢点 慢点
Relax.
别激动
Uncle,
叔
take it easy.
慢点
How's it going?
怎么样
Our Little Watermelon.
我们的小西瓜
Lanxiang,
兰香
don't help him. Let him walk on his own.
你别扶他 让他自己走
I know.
知道啦
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜
be a good baby.
你听话 你听话
Look at her.
你看
Little Watermelon
这小西瓜
is smiling at me.
你冲我乐呢
You know, babies grow so fast
我跟你说这小孩啊
and change every day.
真是一天一个样
That's so true.
那是
Just wait until the second half of
等下半年
the year when An has her second child.
安安再生了二胎
You'll be super busy then.
有的你忙的
I've been eagerly waiting for that day.
我天天都盼着呢
I've been so anxious.
都都 都急坏了
Jing, you've been running around town
他大姑 你看这段时间
during this period.
你两边跑
Xin,
心心
what happened?
怎么了
It's broken.
碎了
Please don't touch it.
你别动
I didn't.
我没动
I want to clean up.
我想收拾收拾
No worries.
别别别
Leave it there.
你放那儿
Let me clean it.
我来啊
Xin,
心心
come on.
来 来
Yeah,
对
sit over here.
你坐这儿啊 来
Be careful
看
not to injure your hands.
别把你手划了
I will take care of the mess.
姐收拾
Mu.
阿木
Ms Xu.
许总监
Sit down.
坐
Head to the tech department to
去一趟技术部
get the data for
调一下这周
the new subscribers this week.
新增用户的数据信息
Also,
顺便看一下
look into their behavior patterns
他们的运行轨迹
Okay.
好
Ms Xu.
许总监
are you looking for Miss Huang?
您找黄副总监
She's not here.
她不在
Well, I'll leave you to it then.
那你们忙吧
How many times do I have to
说了多少遍
remind you to unlock the door?
进门要反锁
You played really well, Mr Zhou.
周总打得真好
Why do you stop playing?
你怎么不打了啊
You need to practice more.
你这球得多练啊
You're well-equipped.
你看你装备也不错
I know, I'm an equipment guy.
是 我 我就是个装备控
I lost interest
我把这些装备
in practicing
都预备齐了
once I collected all the equipment.
也就不练了
Mr Zhou, I've heard
周总 我听说您这个
you also excel in
马术啊 网球啊 足球
horse riding, tennis, and soccer.
都特别擅长
I'm only dabbling in these sports
我就是瞎玩
as I have plenty of free time.
空闲时间比较多
With Wendy
因为温蒂呢
helping us make money,
帮我们赚钱嘛
I've got more time to relax and have fun.
我就能腾出时间去玩了
Well,
你们
how often do you get to
离婚之后 你
see your kids after the divorce?
经常看孩子吗
I usually see them
我一般都是
during visiting hours.
探望时间去看看
Every weekend,
每周末于总
Mr Yu spends a whole day with the kids.
都有一天时间陪孩子
All day?
一整天吗
What if you have work to do?
那有工作怎么办啊
Sometimes, I send the kids to
我有时候有工作也会
their grandparents
把孩子们送到
when I'm working.
爷爷奶奶那边去
They miss their grandchildren, too.
老人有时候也想孩子
But you're their father.
可是你当爸爸的
You don't spend much time with them.
不陪孩子
And the kids don't mind?
孩子没意见吗
I really admire Wendy.
我觉得温蒂很厉害啊
No matter how busy she is,
无论工作多忙
she can take care of the kids herself.
她必须亲自照顾孩子
Really.
真的
I believe that sometimes women
我觉得有时候女性啊
surpass men.
真的比男性要伟大
Wendy can juggle
她可以同时
multiple responsibilities at once.
处理很多问题
She can handle work and family
也可以同时兼顾
duties simultaneously.
职场和家庭
She can take care of household tasks
又能把家务做好
and tidy up herself
还能把自己
at the same time.
收拾得很利索
But some men can't even
但你说男性
get the job
你说光工作一项
done properly.
就做不好
What do you think about that, Wendy?
是不是 温蒂
Come on.
没有 没有
Well, men do
这个 男性嘛
tend to be quite confident.
通常是非常有自信的
I think we women should pick up on
我觉得这一点吧
that confidence thing from them.
值得我们女性学习
Am I right, Mr Yu?
对吧 于总
Mr Yu is a very confident man.
于总就很自信
Mr Yu,
于总啊
I really believe it's crucial for you
我真的觉得你
to make more time
平时要多拿出点时间来
to support Wendy
帮温蒂分担一下
in caring for the children.
照顾孩子的这个担子
This way, Wendy can
这样温蒂就能
help me earn more money.
多帮我赚钱
I don't want to bother Mr Yu.
还是算了吧
I can do it myself.
我自己可以的
Let Mr Yu
还是让于总
efficiently manage Blue Ocean
好好经营蓝海
so, that he can
这样呢
help you earn more money.
也可以帮您多赚点钱
That's true.
也是
Does the investment project of Yaohui Co.
那温蒂
on Blue Ocean
蓝海传媒
get off the ground, Wendy?
耀辉要投了吗
Yep, it's in the works
是 已经上了投委会
at the investment committee. I'm
我准备呢
planning to team up with
联合其他几家机构
a few other organizations on this.
咱们一起
Mr Yu,
于总
I like to joke around,
我这个人爱开玩笑啊
so, don't take my words too seriously.
我的话别放在心上
You can consult Wendy on the project.
项目的事情听温蒂的
Wendy is in charge of it.
她是项目的负责人
Excuse me for a phone call.
我去打个电话
You guys have a good chat.
你们好好聊
Sit here.
你坐
Okay.
好
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You've done a big favor for me.
你这可帮了我大忙了
Although we're divorced,
你看 咱们都离婚了
you're still willing to help me.
你还这么帮我
Listen,
我跟你说啊
the financing option carries risks.
这融资 是有风险的
I'm aware of it.
这我知道
Managing Blue Ocean by myself
但是
for so long has been a real challenge.
比起这些年
Getting some financial support
我一个人维持蓝海
would ease the burden.
太幸福了
So, I'm willing to take a risk
所以我想借这个机会
for the future of Blue Ocean.
我赌一把
See you next week, Mr Yu.
好的 下周见
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Well.
那个
How's the conversation going?
聊得怎么样
Thanks, Mr Zhou.
那个谢谢周总
I really appreciate your help.
非常非常感谢您
You've helped me resolve
您帮我解决了
the financing issue
困扰我们蓝海多年的
affecting Blue Ocean for years.
融资问题
Thank you so much.
谢谢 谢谢
You should thank Wendy,
别谢我 谢温蒂
as she's the one managing the project.
她是项目的负责人
Wendy,
温蒂
come with me
下个礼拜呢
on a business trip next week.
跟我出趟差
It's for a project with Huanan Group.
华南集团的项目
Next week?
下周啊
How long will it take?
需要几天
It will take a week.
一个礼拜
What's wrong?
怎么了
It's okay, Mr Zhou.
没事 周总
Next week is
下周
our daughter's birthday.
我们女儿过生日
It's okay.
没关系
I'll adjust the schedule
那个生日会我会调整
to hold the birthday party earlier.
我可以提前过
I'll definitely follow up on the project.
华南的项目 我一定跟
Okay, it's a deal.
好 那就这么定了
Okay.
好
Mr Yu,
于总
would you like to continue playing?
再打会儿
Sure, I'll watch you play.
行 您打 您打
Go ahead.
您打
Will Xin find a new maternity matron
心心这个育儿嫂走了
now that the previous one has left?
还找吗
I'm not sure.
不知道呢
Xin believes that the previous matron
家里本来有个阿姨
couldn't take good care of the baby,
那心心非嫌人家
so now she wants to hire
不会看孩子
someone new with a higher salary.
要花高价钱请个月嫂
In my opinion, women have a natural
我就觉得女人看孩子
ability to take care of their babies.
天生就应该会吧
Mrs Xu,
亲家母
you cannot think that way.
你可不能这么想啊
It's a matter of professionals
这个呀 就是专业的人
doing professional work.
干专业的事
I also realized this
我也是学了
after I learned the specialty of
母婴护理师以后
maternal-child nursing.
我才知道的
Well, I'm well-trained.
我不就是母婴护理师吗
I can take care of the baby.
我可以带孩子啊
Lanxiang also has relevant experience.
兰香也当过月嫂
So, there are two professionals here.
咱们家有两
Why bother to fire a new one?
干吗还找啊
As long as Xin stays here,
只要心心回来住
I can help her care for the baby.
我就能带
It's a deal.
就这么定了
Lanxiang,
兰香
let's divide the work.
咱俩倒班
I'll take the day shift and come in
白天是我
whenever I have nothing to do at home.
我在家没事干我就来了
You can handle the night shift.
晚上你就来带
The two of us can be just
我就不相信
as good as one maternity matron.
咱俩还顶不上一个月嫂
You're right.
顶得上 顶得上
We can do it.
顶得上
Okay.
行了
I'm going to cook
我呀 去给心心
some delicious food for Xin.
做点好吃的
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜 你听话
be a good baby.
你听话
Come on.
来
You're bored, are you?
坐不住了 坐不住了
Let's go out and have some fun.
咱出去玩玩
I know you are feeling bored.
这也太无聊了
and have some fun.
不老坐这儿
Let's go hang out
出去逛逛
and check out what's out there.
看看有什么好玩的呀
Come on.
走啦
Mom,
妈妈
I missed you so much.
我好想你啊
What took you so long to see me?
你怎么才来呀
I thought you'd forgotten me.
我还以为你把我忘了呢
Don't be silly.
是不是傻
How could I forget you?
妈妈怎么会忘了你呢
Did you listen to Grandma and Grandpa?
有没有听姥姥 姥爷话
What's up?
怎么了
what are you thinking about?
想什么呢
I guess I know
我大概知道
the trick Huang Sisi used.
黄思思用的什么招了
What trick?
什么招
Wait.
来
Ms Xu.
许总监
here's the backend data you want.
你要的后台数据
I've identified that
帮您找到了
most of the users
大部分是年轻的
are young male,
男性用户
which boosts our website's
的确提升了我们网站的
user activities.
用户活跃度
What about behavior patterns?
行动轨迹呢
These users
这些用户
typically spend time on pages
基本都在
featuring attractive women
漂亮小姐姐的页面停留
and often leave...
留言也比较
Vulgar comments.
低俗
Huang Sisi
黄思思
is using revealing pictures of women
是在网上获取一些
found on the internet
女性用户的清凉照片
and posting them on our website
然后通过我们的网站
as a marketing strategy
向外投放 营销
to increase website traffic.
最后达到引流的目的
What has she done to our website?
这我们网站成什么了
I feel like my work
瞬间觉得我自己
has been undermined.
都跟着低俗了
This can't go on,
这可不行啊
Meng'an.
梦安
You must step in.
这你得管哪
Revise the report,
重新做一份报告
and I'll reach out to Mr Zhang.
我去找一趟张总
Okay.
好
It's so disgusting.
恶心
Xin,
心心
Jing.
静姐
I've prepared
那个姐给你做了
a bowl of bird's nest soup for you.
一碗燕窝
Enjoy it while it's hot.
趁热喝了吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Don't mention it.
别说谢
We're a family,
咱不是一家人嘛
are we?
对吧
During your time at home,
你回到家以后啊
focus on being happy.
就高高兴兴的
Try not to overthink things.
别胡思乱想
Make sure to eat well and get enough rest.
好好吃饭 好好睡觉
When you have free time,
没事
play with
多跟小西瓜
Little Watermelon and
一起玩一玩
talk to your
然后跟爸爸妈妈
mom and dad.
也多交流一下
Remember, there's no need to be afraid.
别害怕
No matter what happens,
有什么事
we're here for you.
我们都会帮你的
You look so beautiful
你看
when you smile.
你笑起来多漂亮
Alright.
好
Then enjoy it.
那你吃吧
Thank you, Jing.
谢谢你 静姐
I'm going to check on Little Watermelon.
我去看看小西瓜
Okay.
好
Women are watching the fun.
女性那是看热闹
Meng'an,
梦安
come on.
来
Mr Zhang.
张总
Ms Xu.
许总监
How convenient
刚好
you're here, Miss Huang.
你也在呢
There's something
有些事情
I need to discuss with you.
可能要跟你们商量一下
Here's the latest
这是最新的
user analysis report.
用户分析报告
Please take a look at it.
你看一下吧
No need.
不看了
Just tell me what you want to say.
你有话直说吧
I think there are some issues
我觉得黄总监
with Miss Huang and her outsourcing team's
和她的外包团队
approach to
在引流方式上面
driving traffic to the website.
有一些问题
Ms Xu, you can directly contact me
有什么问题
if you have any concerns about my team's
许总监
efforts to boost website traffic.
你可以直接问我啊
As soon as my approach works,
我的操作
it's okay.
行之有效就行了
My marketing strategy
通过这波引流
has attracted
我们增加了很多
many male users to our website,
男性用户
making up for
这以前
Xinmiao's shortcomings.
可一直都是新苗的短板
Yeah.
对对对
You know, Meng'an,
梦安 我跟你说
the investors
这投资人哪
are very happy with
对我们这数据
how much traffic our website is getting.
还是很满意的
So, you knew about this?
所以你知道这事
I'm curious,
那我就想问问
is there anything else
还有什么事情
you're keeping from me,
是我这个内容总监
the content director?
不知道的吗
Don't be upset.
不是
I just want you to relax a bit,
你这不怀着孕呢吗
especially since you're pregnant.
我想让你少操点心
Mr Zhang,
但是 张总
you can't take that risk.
这样不行的
You're putting Xinmiao
你会把新苗
in jeopardy.
放在风险当中的
Meng'an,
梦安哪
please try not to overreact.
别太紧张了
If any inappropriate comments
你如果出现
come up,
什么不好的言论呢
we can delete them.
咱把它删了不就完了吗
Well,
那个
Miss Huang,
黄副总监
please inform the tech department
你跟技术部门打个招呼
to pay attention to content risk control.
做好内容监控
Sure.
会的
There will be more refinements
以后还会有很多
to come,
细化操作跟上的
so, don't worry.
放心
No,
不是
this is not acceptable.
这 不行的呀
You can't use such a
你们不能用
straightforward and inappropriate method
这么简单粗暴的方式
to increase traffic.
去引流的
What type of image
那让他们
do you want users to
觉得我们新苗是一个
associate with our platform?
什么样的平台啊
We have built up years of
这 这么多年
word-of-mouth
积攒下来的口碑
and a strong reputation.
还有美誉度
Are you willing to throw that away?
这 都不要了吗
This is how the industry,
业内都是这么操作的
including Blue Ocean, functions.
包括蓝海
I don't care how others do it,
别人怎么做我不管
but we can't operate in the same way.
新苗不行
We are capable of setting our own path.
我们不是没有能力的
Why do we have to
为什么要走
follow others' old path,
别人的老路呢
especially in such a
而且用这么低俗的
crude manner?
方式吗
Meng'an,
不是 梦安
we both
你我啊
have a background
都是从传统媒体
in traditional media.
转型过来的
Among those who understand you,
你要说了解你的人呢
I'm one of them.
我算一个
You've got your professional standards
你呢 有职业操守
and bottom line,
有底线
which is excellent.
这很好
But let's face it.
但是你看看现在
The market is so competitive today.
市场竞争多么激烈啊
What do investors focus on?
人投资人看的是什么
It's user numbers,
看的是用户数
daily activity,
日活量
and traffic data.
是数据呀
Let's drop the noble souls talk, okay?
咱别老讲情怀 行吗
Survival is the priority,
咱们在生存面前
so, why not adjust
把这标准啊 放低一点
our standards accordingly?
可以吗
I really can't accept it, Mr Zhang.
真的不行的 张总
Traditional mindset and conservative
传统思维 保守操作
operation can't gnaw the bones
是啃不下下沉市场
of the sinking market.
这块骨头的
Are you bent on stepping on the red line?
你要踏红线啃骨头吗
Do you know what the consequences
你知道新苗会承受
will be for Xinmiao?
什么样的后果吗
Call it off.
叫停吧
We can't call it off, Mr Zhang.
不能停 张总
Why are you so irritable?
你怎么那么暴躁呢
It's not good for the baby.
你这对孩子不好
Well,
那个
she's pregnant.
她啊 怀孕了
The hormonal changes
她喜欢这个
are making her stubborn.
这 钻牛角尖
Don't take her words to heart.
没事 没事
Nah,
你知道我不是
I'm the content director for Xinmiao.
我是新苗的内容总监
I'm responsible for
我在对新苗
the content that Xinmiao publishes.
输出的内容负责
Then, I need to be
那我还得
responsible for the investors.
对投资人负责呢
So what?
那怎么着
Xinmiao needs to raise funds.
它新苗 它要融资
It needs to expand.
要壮大
The strategy is only for the short term.
这又不是长久的策略
It's okay as long as
我们加强监管监控
we tighten supervision and monitoring.
不就完了吗
Alright,
行吧
if that's what you want and I've already
既然你们坚持
informed you of all the potential risks,
我也做到了告知的义务
then I'll leave you be.
你们继续吧
I quit.
我退出
Sorry for the bother.
打扰了
What did he say?
怎么说
I can't persuade him.
管不了
What does that mean?
什么意思啊
He wants performance
他要业绩
and data traffic.
要流量
What are his moral limits?
不要脸啦
Ms Xu.
许总监
Mr Zhou.
小周总
You are both here.
都在呢
What can I do for you?
有事啊
It's nothing big.
没什么事
I was just checking
就是想问问你这两天
when you're free in the next few days.
什么时候有空啊
Can you come with me to Mr Lin's company?
陪我去趟林总公司呗
Wait,
林总公司
isn't our project
他那个项目
with his company done?
不是都结束了吗
Yeah, it is.
是
The project is finished,
项目是结束了
but he still hasn't paid us.
但是这账一直没结
I've reminded him twice, but he's
我都去要了两次了
dragging his feet on making the payment.
林总这推三阻四的
Why do you ask me to accompany you?
那我去是
I'm just thinking that
我这不是想着 你这
you're pregnant.
也大着个肚子嘛 是吧
Mr Lin won't reject my request
你说你这样去
if you come with me.
林总也不好意思拒绝啊
Anyway, you're not busy these days,
反正你最近也没什么事
why don't you come with me?
陪我走一趟呗
Are you trying to use me to gain sympathy?
卖惨吗
I guess that might work a little.
可能能有个些许同情分
Why don't you break your arm?
那你把你胳膊打折吧
Mr Lin would be more sympathetic
林总知道了
if he knew.
同情分会更高
Okay, okay.
得得得
I'm sorry.
我错了
Forget it
当我没说
Watch out for your baby.
别动了胎气
That's ridiculous.
这都什么跟什么呀
Mom,
妈妈
when are we going back to our house?
我们什么时候回自己家
When did you
你什么时候把行李
pack your bags?
都收拾好了
I just unpacked all the clothes.
妈妈刚把衣服都摊开
I'm going to stay at
准备在
Grandma's for a few more days.
外婆家多住几天呢
But I'm homesick,
可是我想家
and miss my dad.
又想我爸
Xiongxiong,
熊熊
I haven't been
妈妈这次
feeling well
生完小西瓜之后呢
since Little Watermelon was born.
觉得身体不太舒服
I want to stay at Grandma and
所以想在外婆外公家
Grandpa's place for a few more days.
多住几天
Could you
你就当陪陪妈妈
stay here
陪陪小西瓜
with Mommy
一块儿住在这儿
and Little Watermelon?
好不好
Mom,
妈妈
did you
你是不是
have another fight with Dad?
又跟我爸吵架了
Come on, Little Watermelon.
来来来 小西瓜
Look at your aunt.
你看你小姑姑呢
She's here.
在这儿 这儿
Now, where's she?
小姑姑呢
There, there.
这儿 这儿
You're ignoring your aunt.
不理小姑姑了
Come on.
来来来
Here, here.
这边 这边
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜
your aunt's here.
姑姑在这里
She,
这个
she is here.
这个小姑姑在这里
Wait, wait, wait.
这这这
My goodness.
我的天哪 这 这怎么
What's going on?
怎么了
Give me a hand
快快快
No, no.
不 不不不
Get down here.
快下来 快下来 快下来
Is there something wrong with the device?
是不是出问题了呀
You look so cute, don't you?
我们是不是好漂亮
You freaked us out.
你快吓死我们了
You're intentional.
你故意的
Give me a break,
你这
you...
你这个
[Dad, Mom says she's]
爸爸 妈妈说
[staying at Grandma's for a long time,]
她要在外婆家住很久
[but I want to go home.]
可是我想回自己家了
[I miss you.]
我想你了
[Dad,]
爸爸
[when are you coming to]
你什么时候来外婆家
[see me at Grandma's?]
看我啊
[Dad.]
爸爸
Don't cry.
不哭 不哭 不哭
Good girl, let me hug you.
好了 大姑抱着走一走
What are you doing?
在干吗呢
I'm in a daze.
我在发呆呢
Really?
发呆哪
How about accompanying me
陪妈妈出去
outside for a walk?
走一走 好不好
Can I buy a lollipop?
那我能买个棒棒糖吗
If you behave well,
你要是听话的话
I'll buy you two.
可以给你买两根
Thank you, mom.
谢谢妈妈
I'm going to change my clothes.
我去换个衣服啊
Wait for a moment.
等等我
Dad!
爸爸
You're here!
爸爸来了
Dad, did you come to pick me up?
爸爸 你是不是来接我的
Son,
儿子
don't you like staying at grandma's?
你不是喜欢在姥姥家吗
Stay a little longer.
多住些日子
No.
不要长住
Stop it.
别闹
I want to go home! I want to go home!
我要回家 我要回家
No, I'm going home.
不 我要回家 回家
Stay here to accompany your sister.
在这儿好好地陪妹妹玩
Don't you want to stay here longer?
你不愿意在这儿长住吗
I brought you your things.
东西我给你带来了
Jia Haowen, what do you mean?
贾浩文 你什么意思啊
Nothing.
没什么意思啊
I'm going on a long trip.
我要出个长差
Dad!
爸爸
Dad, don't leave!
爸爸 你别走
I'm good.
没事
Stay here.
住着
Yunjie.
云阶
I'm here.
来了
Look, Yunjie.
快 云阶
Your Auntie made you fermented rice buns.
大姑给你做的酒酿馒头
Have some.
吃点吧
Thank you, Auntie.
谢谢大姑
Aren't you joining us?
你不一起吃啊
I'll take He Lu's car to go to school.
我搭何璐家车走
See you later.
拜拜
You asked for it.
活该
Are you two still
你们娘儿俩
not talking to each other?
还冷战呢
It's Yunjie
她
who gave me the silent treatment.
应该是她跟我冷战吧
That's tricky.
不好办哪
Lin,
老公
do you think I did the wrong thing?
你说我这事做得有错吗
Anyway, my daughter is right.
反正我觉得我闺女没错
Then I'm not wrong either.
那我觉得我也没错呀
Zhu Kexin's family
那朱可欣家
is having a tough time.
都那么可怜了
Can't we be more lenient with her?
就不能有点包容心吗
Zhu Kexin made the mistake at first.
朱可欣有错在先
Yunjie only wants
我闺女只是要一个
a face-to-face apology.
当面的道歉
It's a simple request.
就是这样
I don't get what you mean
我不知道你说的这个
by being more lenient with her.
包容的点在哪儿啊
So,
那
what should I do?
那我怎么办呢
Please don't rely on me.
怎么办
You've got to resolve it yourself.
自己找办法喽
Find a way out for Yunjie to forgive you.
找个台阶下喽
How?
怎么找啊
Shall I spell it out for you?
还要我教你啊
What does Yunjie enjoy?
你闺女喜欢什么
What's her favorite food?
爱吃什么
In dealing with our matters,
那我下台阶的时候
you have to have my back.
你得扶着我点
I'll make sure to support you.
我还得背着你呢
Deal.
行
Come on.
吃饭
Here it is.
来来来
I made some rice cakes.
我做了米粿
After you guys finish work today,
晚上你俩下班以后啊
remember to pick up Yunjie from school
把云阶一接
and take her to her grandpa's for dinner.
就上她姥爷家吃饭吧
I've got to look after Xin's baby.
我要去给心心带孩子
Don't bother.
不用那么麻烦
If you can't come back to cook,
你要回不来做饭的话
I can do it.
我可以做呀
I'm not busy at work right now.
我现在公司又不忙
Forget it.
算了吧
Is your cooking edible?
你做的饭能吃吗
I'll do it.
我做
Whatever. Either one of you can do it.
随便 你们俩谁做都行
I'm okay with that.
我无所谓
Meng'an,
梦安
I've got something to tell you.
有个事我想跟你说一下
I've noticed
我发现呀
something's up with Xin.
最近心心有点不太对
What's up with her?
她怎么了
Let me tell you.
你看啊
She's been acting stubborn,
爱钻牛角尖
always up for an argument,
爱抬杠
and quick to lose her temper.
脾气大
These are
这些呀
all signs of postpartum depression.
都是产后抑郁症的倾向
I have experience in caregiving,
我过去不是干过护理吗
and I understand that
我知道 一个人哪
when someone is
她要是自己身体
physically uncomfortable,
不舒服啊
they can quickly become irritable.
那脾气大着呢
If their family neglects them,
要是家里人再嫌弃啊
their condition will worsen.
那她心里就更难受了
Who neglects Xin?
谁嫌弃她呀
The whole family is good to her.
家里没人嫌弃她呀
Where did your
你以前那些
sharpness go?
领悟力去哪儿了
You've become slow-minded now.
脑子不灵啊 你现在
Xin had her second kid,
梦心生了二胎了
and now everyone's
全家所有的注意力
all about the baby.
都在孩子身上
Is she feeling overlooked?
她是不是会有失落感
So,
那 那就
we have to show her some extra love.
多关心关心她呗
Yes,
对
that's what I mean.
我就是这个意思
When you're available,
你没事啊
regularly visit Xin
多去看看她
and catch up with her.
和她聊聊天
Okay,
去
I got it.
我去
Come on.
那吃饭吧
You're right.
也是
Xin has gone through a lot
心心生这二胎
to have a second baby.
确实遭了不少罪呢
Don't eat the egg yolks.
蛋黄别吃
Oh, you take this.
那那 这给你
Okay.
好
Have one more?
再来一个
Why are you being so quiet today?
今天怎么那么安静啊
Would you like to listen to some music
要不要听会儿音乐
or a lecture?
还是听个讲座
No, I don't think so.
不了吧
I can sense
我现在能体会到
the emotions
他们之前说的那个
they were expressing earlier.
心情了